The Modern Phreakers Guide To Payphones

 The Modern Phreakers Guide To Payphones
by: datachild

*Note: This tutorial is for semi experienced phreakers... if you dont
understand something then go read other tutorials because this one isnt
for you. I made it so you'd have a little more up to date information on
payphones... not my best work but informative


Table Of Contents
I. Introduction
II. Types Of Payphones
III. Boxes you’ll Need
IV. Tools You’ll need
V. Methods of Payphone Exploitation
VI. Other Ideas
VII. Greets



Introduction://
Well whats every phreaks dream? Free payphone calls! But getting
free payphone calls isn’t that easy or that stealthy. I will go through
the ways to get around them but be warned this can get you jail time and
or a big ass fine. Also this is for people who have certain boxes made.
I don’t tell you how to make any of these boxes in this tutorial.

Types of Payphones://
There are 2 types, COCOTS and Mah Bell phones. COCOTS are owned by
local business owners and aren’t run by the phone company. Bell/Verizon
phones are… They are easy to tell the difference because Mah Bell phones
will have the word “Bell” or “Verizon”. Holly shit that was hard!

Boxes You’ll Need://
Hehe the boxes. Ok well contrary to what most people believe, redboxes
still work today… omg yes they do! Heh, but only on certain types of phones.
You’ll need a beige box too.

Tools You’ll Need://
Welp, you’ll just need the usual tools and a new addition. Ya need
Wire Cutters, Wire Skinner, screw driver, and a Hacksaw (These come in
pocket knives so I suggest you get one bish)

Methods of Payphone Exploitation://
Here we go; I will break this up into two categories
MahBell and COCOTs.

-COCOT-
Ok well here is were im not too experienced, so I’ll go from what
I told still works, if it doesn’t then oh fuck I’m so sorry ;). COCOTS
are payphones set up by the simple people. They run off of regular phone
wires and 90% of the time the wires don’t run underground…. So hey guess
what… if it’s a regular phone wire… then we can beige box it right? RIGHT!
So there are 2 ways of doing this. The obvious and the not so obvious. The
obvious is to cut the wire that runs from the handset to the actual phone
and clip in your beige box,, the not so obvious is to follow the wires that
run down the payphone up to the wall of the building, you should see a little
medal box that you can unscrew, you can expose the wires here and clip in.
Another way of doing this is to use a redbox. But redboxes don’t work on a
COCOT without having to socially engineer the operator. So here’s what ya
do; call “0” and tell the operator that someone put gum all over the keys
and you need her to place a call for you. When she asks for money play the
tones on your redbox, it works beautifully were I live, people
in Mississippi don’t know shit ;).

-Mah Bell-
Mah bell phones? EASY SHIT! These can be redboxed!!! Atleast they
can were I live. Go find a tutorial on how to make a redbox somewere and
use it! If the phones have some type of protection against them, use the
operator trick I told you about earlier.

Other Ideas://
I had some ideas for COCOTS. What if you set up a modified portable
phone at a COCOT… so you could pick up your handset and fuck around with
the person?! Wouldn’t that be great!? You’d get calling card numbers and
you could harass people!. I was inspired from a story on www.phonelosers.org.
Hah well yeah ok that’s my 2 cents.

Greets://
I don’t love anyone
